ELAINE SALAS

INSTRUCTOR





Eeb.sala@gmail.com



in Linkedin.com/in/lainesalas

About

Art Instructor and Freelance Graphic Designer, experienced in teaching art classes and workshops by customizing curriculum and lesson plans which also include those hybrid-remote learning. Designing freelance has offered support with local artists with brand presence, logo designs and mixed media pieces.

Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Graphic Design

Bob Jones University, SC Aug 2013 - May 2016

Associates, Commercial Arts

Rio Hondo, CA Aug 2006 - May 2008

Design Skills

Adobe Creative Cloud

Photoshop, Illustator, InDesign

Affinity

Designer

Canva

Layout Design

Procreate

Photography

Internship

Graphic Designer

Jan 2016 - April 2016 Upward Star Sports, SC

Multi-Sport venue offering programs for young athletes. Internship included high demands of designs, facilitating and contributing to brainstorming sessions to promote creativity in marketing campaigns.

Experience

Creative Arts Instructor

Sept 2017-Jan 2022 Able ARTS Work, Long Beach CA Development of art-based curriculum and portfolio work to ensure clients opportunities within the art community, alongside art and music therapists.

LAUSD Online Zine Workshop

Oct 2020-Feb 2021

Rancho Dominguez Preparatory School, CA Hybrid workshop; Introducing Zines and other various self-published pieces of work.

LBUSD Bottle Cap Mural Workshop

Oct 2019-Mar 2019

Patrick Henry Elementary School, CA Interactive workshop collaboratively using recycled materials for innovative mural pieces.

Ceramic Studio Assistant

Aug 2015-May 2016

Division of Art and Design Ceramic Studio, SC Responsible for maintaining the upkeep of studio space to ensure safe reliable equipment for the classroom and supervision of kiln firing.

Professional References

Christina Ebersole
Clinical Training Director
+ (310) 938-2181
Cebersole@ableartswork.org

James Brooks

Accessible Arts Workshops Coordinator + (661) 992-9480

Jbrooks@ableartswork.org

Heidi Tulcan

Assistant Program Manager + (562) 298-3013 Htulcan@ableartswork.org

Personal References

Raul Manzo - (323) 719-3257 Thejuny@yahoo.com

John Romana + (714) 478-8768 Jbm.romana@gmail.com

Involvement

Zine Virtual Workshop with Anaheim Library

Aug 2021 - Sept 2021

Demonstrated and provided instruction on how to create zines and other self-published pieces of work.

Bergamot Station - CORE Art Show

May 2021

Earned a residency at Santa Monica which transferred to the gallery space off of 2nd and PCH exhibiting client and curators collaborative work.

Launching of "Learn for Life"

March 2020 - July 2020

Created and edited video content for the companies YouTube channel.

Judge for the Port of Long Beach, Photo Program

Participant in jurying 50 entries of 300 contestants based on creative criteria. - Oct 2019

Exhibiting at the Long Beach Zinefest

Hosted a booth promoting awareness, client artwork, zines and products - May 2019

Member of the American Advertising Federation

Aug 2015 - 2017 Greenville, SC

Collaboration

Long Beach Gives

Annual fundraiser supporting with donor relationships Sept 2019 - Sept 2021

Yamaha Cares

Upcycled guitar exhibit- March 2021

The Process: Exposed

A virtual photography exhibit - August 2020

Who & With Photo Show

Photography art show - June 2019

On A Roll

Casino night fundraiser - May 2019

ArtBeat Radio

Winner of The Big Score video contest - April 2019

Happy Together

Opera Performance with The Infinate Stage - Dec 2018